Now, most of the code that you've written has been synchronous, and
الآن، معظم الأكواد التي كتبتها تمت مزامنتها،
this means that each line of code gets executed one right after another.
وهذا يعني أن كل سطر تم تنفيذه واحدًا تلو الآخر.
And you must wait for each line to finish executing before going on to
وعليك انتظار الانتهاء من تنفيذ كل سطر قبل الذاهاب إلى
the next line, but recently we've been learning about asynchronous callbacks.
السطر التالي، لكننا تعلمنا مؤخرًا أمورًا بشأن الاستجابات غير المتزامنة.
And this means that we tell the system we're interested in a certain event,
وهذا يعني أننا نقول للنظام نحن مهتمون بحدث معين،
like a click event, and then tell the system to notify us,
مثل حدث النقر، ثم أخبر النظام لإعلامنا،
or call us back when that event happens.
أو الاتصال بنا مرة أخرى عندما حدوث هذا الحدث.
And in the meantime, we can go do something else in the app, and
وفي هذه الأثناء، يمكننا فعل شيء آخر في التطبيق،
that means we're not sitting around stalled or waiting for
وهذا يعني أننا لن ننتظر
the user to click on the button on the screen.
أن ينقر المستخدم على الزر الموجود في الشاشة.
And when the event happens, or if it even happens at all, then
وعند حدوث الحدث،
the system will call us back and we can execute instructions that we specified.
سيتصل النظام بنا مرة أخرى ويمكننا تنفيذ التعليمات التي حددناها.
So the on click listener callback and the list views
ومن ثم تستجيب وظيفة onclicklistener
on I don't click listener callback were both examples of asynchronous callbacks.
وطرق عرض القائمة، وظيفة clicklistener كانت مثالا على استجابات غير المتزامنة.
So for example, we only want to play the audio file for each word when the system
لذلك على سبيل المثال، نريد فقط تشغيل ملف صوتي لكل كلمة
calls us back and tells us that a certain list item was clicked on.
عند رد النظام علينا وإخبارنا بعنصر قائمة محدد تم النقر فوقه.
This means that in that time while we're waiting, we can still do other things
وهذا يعني أنه في وقت الانتظار، لا يزال بوسعنا أن نفعل أشياء أخرى
like scroll the list, or wait for other user input events.
مثل تمرير القائمة، أو انتظار أحداث إدخال المستخدم الأخرى.
So doing something while we're waiting for an event to happen and
ولذلك فعل أي شيء أثناء انتظار وقوع أي حدث
then jumping back into action is called an asynchronous callback.
ثم العودة مرة أخرى إلى العمل هو استدعاء غير متزامن.
And so for sure you might sometimes hear it called async callbacks.
ومن المؤكد أنك تسمعها في بعض الأحيان
So A-S-Y-N-C, async callback.
وبالتالي A-S-Y-N-C تعني استدعاء غير متزامن.
Now, as you learn more about Android development,
والآن، بما أنك عرفت الكثير عن تطوير آندرويد،
you will realize that async callbacks are a common pattern in Android for
فأنت تعرف أن الاستدعاءات غير المتزامنة نمط مشترك في آندرويد
us to set up listeners for events on the device.
لإعداد المستمعين للإحداث في الجهاز.
And so, for example, there are listeners for when the user's location changes.
وهكذا، على سبيل المثال، هناك مستمعون عند تغيير موقع المستخدم.
Now in order for your app to behave as a user expects, you need to be able to
الآن كي يتفاعل تطبيقك مع توقع المستخدم، يجب أن تكون قادرا على
hook into these and be able to handle those cases properly.
وربطها بهذه الحالات، وأن تكون قادرًا على التعامل مع تلك الحالات على الوجه الصحيح.
Now, let's learn more about another callback.
الآن، دعونا نتعلم المزيد عن رد آخر.
So the media player API offers several so
واجهة مشغل الموسيقى تعرض العديد
that developers can get notified when certain events happen.
حيث يتمكن المطورون من الحصول على إشعارات عند وقوع أحداث معينة.
Specifically, there's a callback that tells us when an audio or
لا سيما، هناك رد يخبرنا عند انتهاء تشغيل
media file has finished playing.
ملف صوتي أو ملف وسائط.
Can you search online to figure out which callback method that is?
هل يمكنك البحث عبر الإنترنت للتعرف على وظيفة الرد هذه؟
And write that answer in this box when you find it.
يمكنك تدوين الإجابة في هذا المربع عندما تعثر عليه.
When you found that answer,
عندما تجد تلك الإجابة،
I like to use that information to modify the sample music player app.
أود استخدام تلك المعلومات لتعديل تطبيق مشغل الموسيقى العينة.
So change the app so
ومن ثم تغيير التطبيق
that when a song is done playing, it pops up a toast message saying I'm done.
عند تشغيل الأغنية، تظهر رسالة منبثقة تقول فعلتها.
Now this step can be a little bit tricky, so
هذه الخطوة قد تكون صعبة قليلًا
take note of the hints that we provided you down below this quiz.
هناك نصائح مقدمة أسفل الاختبار.